

Profile

Result-oriented individual with strong communication and collaborative skills. I bring experience with object-oriented design, the ability to code with a variety of languages, experience with agile and scrum methodologies, and a strong and reliable work ethic.

■ Employment History

Associate Software Engineer at Verint | Remote, CA

August 2022 — Present

- Demonstrated proficiency in the codebase, documentation, JIRA, and correct development processes for streamlined project management and development.
- Reviewed newly acquired codebase, provided valuable feedback on project structure, design patterns, and identified and resolved code issues.
- Developed a configuration utility that improved user experience and expedited the setup process for consumers.
- Expanded skillset by learning a new tech stack and integrated unit tests to
 ensure the functionality of newly acquired company repositories while
 also performing accessibility tests to meet industry standards.

Senior Customer Specialist at CarMax | Pleasant Hill, CA

June 2019 — August 2022

- Spearheaded store operations, emphasizing sales process and budget management, resulting in increased profitability, improved customer satisfaction, and the development of associates' skills, showcasing strong leadership and management abilities.
- Oversaw vendor activities, ensuring excellent customer service and efficient administration per contracts and performance guarantees, demonstrating strong project management skills.
- Led the team in setting strategy for the store, providing team members with a clear vision, direction, and motivation, highlighting strong communication and leadership skills.

Software Developer at Peritik Jewelry | Bay Point, CA

December 2018 — April 2019

- Led the redesign of a website, focusing on improving customer engagement and navigation while also integrating Shopify CRM for better control of customer orders and data.
- Played a pivotal role in every aspect of the product development process, from ideation to development and improvement, resulting in features

Details

Concord, CA, 94521

925-726-6403

gonzalezhilariojose@gmail.com

Links

https://hilario.io

https://github.com/Hilarioo https://www.linkedin.com/in/h

ilariooo/

Skills

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe XD

AJAX

Amazon Web Services

Axios

Azure

CI/CD

Confluence

C++

DOM Manipulation

Express.js

Figma

Git

HTML & CSS

il8n

Jira

Java

JavaScript

Jest

jQuery

Pinia

that reached over 15,000 monthly users, showcasing strong skills in front-end development and design.

 Reduced customer support requests by 30% by implementing ManyChat, automating Facebook messaging to provide a more efficient and streamlined customer experience.

Coding Instructor at Code 4 Kids | Brentwood, CA

August 2017 — June 2018

- Led the planning and execution of comprehensive lesson plans and instructional activities for 4-5th grade students, tailored to individual students' proficiency in computers and programming.
- Developed and implemented an engaging after-school curriculum that introduced students to the basics of programming, emphasized its importance, and culminated in a small project using HTML and CSS, showcasing strong skills in front-end development and design.
- Maintained clear and consistent communication with parents regarding student progress, goals, and any potential barriers to success, utilizing multiple preferred methods of communication such as email and SMS.

Projects

Weather App

July 2022

- Designed and developed a responsive weather web app that allows users to view current and future weather conditions based on location, leveraging user IP addresses to provide localized data.
- Implemented using: React, Typescript, Context API, Axios, Date-fns, Jest, NodeJS, and MaterialUI

Donut Music

May 2022

- full-stack web application featuring a violin, guitar, drums, and flute as
 instruments and four unique visualizers. Our visualizers react to the amps,
 hertz, and/or speed of the song or key playing.
- Implemented using: TypeScript, React + Redux, Node.js, p5.js, tone.js, socket.io, and sqlite3

Recipe IOS App

January 2022

- Design and implement a recipe app allowing users to create an account, and find new recipes to cook at random or by genre.
- Implemented using: Swift, SwiftUI, Firebase Auth, SpoonacularAPI, and Xcode

Portfolio Website

June 2021 - present

- Design and implement a dynamic mobile-first website to display achievements and information about me and my projects.
- Implemented using: HTML5, CSS, Vanilla Javascript, DOM Manipulation, and Netlify

Python

Markdown

MongoDB

MUI

Node.js

React

REST API

SQL

Socket IO

Swift

Tailwind CSS

Testing Library

Typescript

Vite

Vitest

Vue Test Utils

Vue 3

Vuetify

Xcode

Languages

English

Spanish

Talent Pipeline Web App

January 2021

- Develop and modularize reactJS components including prop and state handling for efficient build optimization and re-usability using Agile Methodologies
- Deploy NodeJS application on AWS EC2 Instance with GitHub
- Led responsive design created with Figma and Adobe Illustrator following Material Design Guidelines
- Implemented using: AWS, Bcrypt, Bootstrap, CSS, Cookie-Parser, Express, Javascript ES6, MySQL, NodeJS, and ReactJS

Multi-User Messaging Web App

January 2020

- Develop a responsive web app that allows users to create an account and message groups of people like Discord
- Integrate asynchronous HTTP requests to REST endpoints to perform CRUD operations with the backend using Axios (a lightweight HTTP client based on the XMLHttpRequests service)
- Implemented using: Axios, JQuery, Java, JavaScript, MongoDB, NodeJS, React-Dom, React

Photo Management Web App

January 2020

- Design responsive user interface and features using AdobeXD and Adobe
 Illustrator
- Develop a responsive web app that allows users to create an account, comment, search and upload images
- Implemented using: Axios, Bcrypt, ExpressJS, Heroku, HTML5/CSS, Javascript, MySQL, NodeJS, and Passport

Education

B.S Computer Science, San Francisco State University, San FranciscoAugust 2019 — May 2022

A.S Mathematics & Physics , Los Medanos College, Pittsburg

August 2015 — May 2017